ILGWU Local 62-32 Agreements 5780/089
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 62-32 Agreements
1966-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Stein, Leon. Local 62-32
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/089
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection includes collective bargaining agreements of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 62-32, Intimate Apparel, Embroidery, Belt and Allied Workers Local.
5493033
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, March 10, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 62-32 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Intimate Apparel, Embroidery, Belt and Allied Workers Local, was based in New York, New York. The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Women's clothing industry--Manitoba--Winnipeg.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--Manitoba--Winnipeg.; Collective bargaining--Clothing workers--United States.; Collective bargaining--Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Collective bargaining--Clothing workers--Manitoba--Winnipeg.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--Manitoba--Winnipeg.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--Manitoba--Winnipeg.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 62 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 32 (Winnipeg, Man.)
5493033
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Productive Workers, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association of New York, Inc.- Productive Workers, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association, Inc.- Office Work Division, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Productive Workers, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Supplemental Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Office Workers Division, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association, Inc.- Productive Workers, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Lingerie Manufacturers Association of New York, Inc.- Productive Workers, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Office Work Division, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Productive Workers [folder 1 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Productive Workers [folder 2 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union- Productive Workers [folder 3 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association, Inc.- Office Work Division, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association, Inc.- Productive Workers [folder 1 of 2], 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Allied Underwear Association, Inc.- Productive Workers [folder 2 of 2], 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 1 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 2 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 3 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 4 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 5 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 6 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 7 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 8 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 9 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 10 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 11 of 11], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 1 of 2], 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 2 of 2], 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 1 of 2], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 2 of 2], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 1 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 2 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 3 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 4 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 5 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 6 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 7 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 8 of 12], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 9 of 12], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 10 of 12], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 11 of 12], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 12 of 12], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 1 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 2 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 3 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 4 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 5 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 6 of 13], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 7 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 8 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 9 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 10 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 11 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 12 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union [folder 13 of 13], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Collective Labor Agreements. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous "Our Union" Materials, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Arbitration between Local 52-32 and Feldman Industries, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)